<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Andrew Miotke</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Andrew Miotke</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 16:30:23 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Automate jamf2snipe with GitHub Actions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/automate_jamf2snipe_with_github_actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 16:30:23 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/automate_jamf2snipe_with_github_actions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Automate the import of Jamf objects into Snipe-IT&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Cron: My notes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/learningcron/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 15:02:30 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/learningcron/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cron job notes&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Docker: My notes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/learningdocker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 15:21:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/learningdocker/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Docker notes&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swift: Markdown Support</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/swift-markdown-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 11:51:22 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/swift-markdown-support/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mardown support in Swift&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SwiftUI: List Card View</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/swiftui-list-card-view/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 10:48:41 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/swiftui-list-card-view/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Creating &amp;lsquo;card views&amp;rsquo; using SwiftUI&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Procrastinating with writing more</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2021-06-01-procrastinating-with-writing-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 14:52:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2021-06-01-procrastinating-with-writing-more/</guid>
      <description>I have decided I want to write more. I&amp;rsquo;m just not sure what, if any, focus I want to have with it. Tech will be the primary focus leaning toward writing code and other tech opinions that come to mind.
This post is my attempt at getting back into writing. In typical form, I found myself sitting down with a cup coffee yesterday morning ready to go. Then I thought about a problem I had and wrote a Python script to solve that problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming soon: AutoMate</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020-08-14-automate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 09:04:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020-08-14-automate/</guid>
      <description>AutoMate is an app to help keep track of your car&amp;rsquo;s maintenance schedule and service history. I am expecting to have this out by the end of Fall 2020 🤞.
If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in downloading and using the TestFlight beta builds, feel free to check it out here: https://testflight.apple.com/join/WwJH6tyO
I&amp;rsquo;ll update this post as I continue to make more progress on the app.
Plans and features Once complete you should be able to add your car(s) and add in your car&amp;rsquo;s full service history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing: Tankd</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020-06-16-tankd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 09:04:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020-06-16-tankd/</guid>
      <description>Introducing Tankd, my first iOS app released in the App Store for iOS!
So the app is called Tankd and simply put it’s a fuel stop tracking app for iOS. I had heard a few times and even talked to a few friends who like to save their receipts at every fuel stop they make. I tried this for a short bit and got frustrated with all of the receipt papers cluttering up areas like the glove box.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First App in TestFlight: Tankd</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020-05-20-first-app-in-testflight/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 09:29:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020-05-20-first-app-in-testflight/</guid>
      <description>I finally did it! Earlier this week I submitted an app to TestFlight for the first time. This is the first step in achieving my goal of submitting an app to the iOS App Store and I could not be more excited. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk more about the app in a moment with a link so you can download it. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to let it bake with testers in TestFlight to work out all the kinks and bugs then move it to the App Store soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portfolio App: Meal Time</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020-04-11-meal-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 15:36:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020-04-11-meal-time/</guid>
      <description>Update As I outlined in A New Hope I&amp;rsquo;m taking this time to refocus my software development efforts on iOS and Swift. It&amp;rsquo;s been about a week and a half since I was laid off of my job and I have taken it in stride. I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to work on a few different types of apps, some &amp;ldquo;portfolio&amp;rdquo; that won&amp;rsquo;t be released on the App Store and at least one that will be released on the App Store.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Hope</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020-03-31-a-new-hope/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 13:56:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020-03-31-a-new-hope/</guid>
      <description>After nearly three years I was let go and lost my job due to the COVID-19 pandemic, yeah, it sucks&amp;hellip;hard. I&amp;rsquo;m now unemployed but thankfully I have a tremendous and supportive wife, family and friends. I really have no idea where I would be without them.
The breakup I found out at the same time as many of my colleagues, Slack exploded and Notification Center on my Mac was trying to keep up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume Gist</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2019-04-06-resume-gist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 10:28:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2019-04-06-resume-gist/</guid>
      <description>For awhile now I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about the resumé, that piece of paper - or nowadays pdf file that we upload to a website or give a recruiter. The rule of thumb I&amp;rsquo;ve always been given is keep it short and sweet and try to keep it all on one page. In today’s world we rarely stay at a company for more than three or four years, how are we supposed to keep all this work experience limited one page?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking Classes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2019-02-17-taking-classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 16:22:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2019-02-17-taking-classes/</guid>
      <description>Taking Classes Well it&amp;rsquo;s that time again, it&amp;rsquo;s time to start looking at taking a new class to continue to grow my fundamentals in programming. This time I found a class at the Univeristy of Washington(UW) and the course is in Python 🐍!
Python is a language that I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to learn for awhile now, once I had an understanding of Swift. I applied for the class last week and I&amp;rsquo;m just waiting to get the &amp;ldquo;acceptance letter&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vision and Purpose</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2018-07-10-vision-and-purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 09:04:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2018-07-10-vision-and-purpose/</guid>
      <description>In my last post I explained my journey up to this point in time and my found passion for Swift. Today I&amp;rsquo;m going to explain the vision and purpose of why this website exists in the first place and what I hope to achieve with it.
Vision My vision for this website is to have a place that I can talk about my various learnings with Swift and other topics as I explore iOS development and developing on Apple platforms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>andrewmiotke.com v2.0</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2018-06-30-welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 17:44:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2018-06-30-welcome/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to andrewmiotke.com v2.0, if you saw my previous website then you know it was aimed at being a web developer, this is taking a whole new turn. Over the last eight months I made the decision to leave what I thought my dreams were, web development(yet here we are on a website) to pursue what I quickly learn was a true passion of mine, iOS development with Swift.
What happened with web?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
